{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {

      "question": "What does the central limit theorem state?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " if the sample size increases sampling distribution must approach normal distribution",
        "b": "if the sample size decreases then the sample distribution must approach normal distribution",
        "c": " if the sample size increases then the sampling distribution much approach an exponential distribution",
        "d": "if the sample size decreases then the sampling distribution much approach an exponential distribution"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation: The central limit theorem states that if the sample size increases sampling distribution must approach normal distribution. Generally a sample size more than 30 us considered as large enough.",
        "b": "Explanation: The central limit theorem states that if the sample size increases sampling distribution must approach normal distribution. Generally a sample size more than 30 us considered as large enough.",
        "c": "Explanation: The central limit theorem states that if the sample size increases sampling distribution must approach normal distribution. Generally a sample size more than 30 us considered as large enough.",
        "d": "Explanation: The central limit theorem states that if the sample size increases sampling distribution must approach normal distribution. Generally a sample size more than 30 us considered as large enough."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {  
       "question": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the sampling distribution of the sample mean is approximately normal if?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "all possible samples are selected",
        "b": "the sample size is large",
        "c": "the standard error of the sampling distribution is small.",
        "d": "the sample size is small"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the sampling distribution of the sample mean is approximately normal if the sample size is large.",
        "b": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the sampling distribution of the sample mean is approximately normal if the sample size is large.",
        "c": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the sampling distribution of the sample mean is approximately normal if the sample size is large.",
        "d": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the sampling distribution of the sample mean is approximately normal if the sample size is large."  },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {
       "question": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "equal to the population mean divided by the square root of the sample size",
        "b": "close to the population mean if the sample size is large",
        "c": "exactly equal to the population mean",
        "d": "equal to the population mean divided by the sample size"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean.",
        "b": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean. ",
        "c": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean.",
        "d": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean."  },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },

    {
       "question": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the standard deviation of the sampling distribution of the sample means is ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "equal to the population standard deviation divided by the square root of the sample size",
        "b": "close to the population standard deviation if the sample size is large",
        "c": "exactly equal to the standard deviation",
        "d": "equal to the population standard deviation divided by the sample size"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "standard deviation is equal to the population standard deviation divided by the square root of the sample size. ",
        "b": "standard deviation is equal to the population standard deviation divided by the square root of the sample size.",
        "c": "standard deviation is equal to the population standard deviation divided by the square root of the sample size. ",
        "d": " standard deviation is equal to the population standard deviation divided by the square root of the sample size."  },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
       "question": "Samples of size 25 are selected from a population with mean 40 and standard deviation 7.5. The mean of the sampling distribution of sample means is?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "7.5",
        "b": "8",
        "c": "40",
        "d": "60"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean, therefore mean=40. ",
        "b": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean, therefore mean=40. ",
        "c": "The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean, therefore mean=40. ",
        "d": " The Central Limit Theorem says that the mean of the sampling distribution of the sample means is exactly equal to the population mean, therefore mean=40. "  },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"

      "question": "The cumulative distribution function of a random variable x is the probability that X takes the value?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "less than or equal to x",
        "b": "equal to x",
        "c": "greater than x",
        "d": "zero"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Let $X$ be a real random variable. The function $F_X$ defined over $R$ through $F_X(x)  :=P_X((-infinity, x]) =P(X =< x)$",
        "b": "Let $X$ be a real random variable. The function $F_X$ defined over $R$ through $F_X(x)  :=P_X((-infinity, x]) =P(X =< x)$",
        "c": "Let $X$ be a real random variable. The function $F_X$ defined over $R$ through $F_X(x)  :=P_X((-infinity, x]) =P(X =< x)$",
        "d": "Let $X$ be a real random variable. The function $F_X$ defined over $R$ through $F_X(x)  :=P_X((-infinity, x]) =P(X =< x)$"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {  
       "question": "Consider two identically distributed zero-mean random variable U and V. Let the cumulative distribution function of U and 2V be F(x) and G(x) respectively. Then, for all values of x.?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "$F(x)-G(x) less than or equal to 0$",
        "b": "$F(x)-G(x)  greater than or equal to 0 0$",
        "c": "$(F(x)-G(x)).x  less than or equal to 0 0$",
        "d": "$(F(x)-G(x)).x  greater than or equal to 0$"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "F(x) is CDF of U than  F(x)= p(U=< x) G(x) is CDF of 2V than G(x)= p(2V=< x) G(x)=p(V=< x/2) given U and V are identical therefore F(x)=p(V=< x) and G(x)=p(V=< x/2) F(x) - G(x)= p(V=< x) - p(V=< x/2) go by option  let x=2 than F(2)-G(2)= p(V=< 2) - p(V=<1) p(V=< x) -> probability from -infinity to x therefore  p(V=< 2) - p(V=<1)≥ 0 ⇒F(x)-G(x)>=0 ",
        "b": " ",
        "c": "for x=-2 F(-2)-G(-2)= p(V=<- 2) - p(V=<-1) p(V=<- 2) ≤  p(V≤-1) -> F(x)-G(x)=< 0 for x =< 0",
        "d": "{F(2)-G(2)}2= {p(V≤ 2) - p(V≤1)}2 {F(x) - G(x)}.x≥ 0 for x≥ 0 now check for x≤ 0  let x=-2 {F(-2)-G(-2)}(-2)= {p(V≤ 2) - p(V≤1)}(-2) {p(V≤ 2) - p(V≤1)}≤ 0 therefore {p(V≤ 2) - p(V≤1)}(-2)≥ 0"  },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {
       "question": "Consider a random variable X that takes values +1 and −1 with probability 0.5 each. The values of the cumulative distribution function F(x) at x = −1 and +1 are?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0 and 0.5",
        "b": "0 and 1",
        "c": "0.5 and 1",
        "d": "0.25 and 0.75"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Given that P(-1) =0.5 and P(1) =0.5. So, at all other points, p must be zero as the sum of all probabilities must be 1. F(X) is the cumulative distribution function and let P is the probability and given X is random variable, So F(X) = P[X ≤ x] F(-1)=P(X <= -1 = P(x = -1) =0.5 and F(1)=P(X <= 1) =P(x = -1) + P(x = 1) =0.5 + 0.5 =1",
        "b": "Given that P(-1) =0.5 and P(1) =0.5. So, at all other points, p must be zero as the sum of all probabilities must be 1. F(X) is the cumulative distribution function and let P is the probability and given X is random variable, So F(X) = P[X ≤ x] F(-1)=P(X <= -1 = P(x = -1) =0.5 and F(1)=P(X <= 1) =P(x = -1) + P(x = 1) =0.5 + 0.5 =1 ",
        "c": "Given that P(-1) =0.5 and P(1) =0.5. So, at all other points, p must be zero as the sum of all probabilities must be 1. F(X) is the cumulative distribution function and let P is the probability and given X is random variable, So F(X) = P[X ≤ x] F(-1)=P(X <= -1 = P(x = -1) =0.5 and F(1)=P(X <= 1) =P(x = -1) + P(x = 1) =0.5 + 0.5 =1",
        "d": " Given that P(-1) =0.5 and P(1) =0.5. So, at all other points, p must be zero as the sum of all probabilities must be 1. F(X) is the cumulative distribution function and let P is the probability and given X is random variable, So F(X) = P[X ≤ x] F(-1)=P(X <= -1 = P(x = -1) =0.5 and F(1)=P(X <= 1) =P(x = -1) + P(x = 1) =0.5 + 0.5 =1"  },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },

    {
       "question": "The probability cumulative distribution must be monotone and ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "increasing",
        "b": "decreasing",
        "c": "non-increasing",
        "d": "non-decreasing"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "CDF is the summation of the Probabilities of discrete random variables. So CDF is always non-decreasing with finitely many jump-discontinuities. ",
        "b": "CDF is the summation of the Probabilities of discrete random variables. So CDF is always non-decreasing with finitely many jump-discontinuities.  ",
        "c": "CDF is the summation of the Probabilities of discrete random variables. So CDF is always non-decreasing with finitely many jump-discontinuities. ",
        "d": " CDF is the summation of the Probabilities of discrete random variables. So CDF is always non-decreasing with finitely many jump-discontinuities. "  },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
       "question": "Consider a discrete random variable Y that takes values -2, -1, 0, 1, and 2 with probability 0.2 each. The values of the cumulative distribution function G(y) at y = -1 and y = 1 are ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.4 and 0.8",
        "b": "0 and 1",
        "c": "0.4 and 0.6",
        "d": "1 and 0"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "G(-1) = p(-2) + p(-1) = 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.4 and G(1) = p(-2) + p(-1) + p(0) + p(1) = 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.8. ",
        "b": "G(-1) = p(-2) + p(-1) = 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.4 and G(1) = p(-2) + p(-1) + p(0) + p(1) = 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.8.   ",
        "c": "G(-1) = p(-2) + p(-1) = 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.4 and G(1) = p(-2) + p(-1) + p(0) + p(1) = 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.8.  ",
        "d": " G(-1) = p(-2) + p(-1) = 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.4 and G(1) = p(-2) + p(-1) + p(0) + p(1) = 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 + 0.2 = 0.8.  "  },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"


}
    ]
}
